Kathryn Ellis

Senior Strategic Consultant

07739013961

kat@kathrynellis.co.uk

I relish seemingly insurmountable problems, love thinking in an unexpected manner and am unapologetically honest. I have 20 years' experience on challenger brands and challenging creative thinking. I thrive on helping companies succeed, and am eager to share my expertise.

Career

Managing Partner, Strategy, McCann Bristol Senior Strategist, Bray Leino, Bristol Senior Strategist, Karmarama, London Strategist, DLKW (Now Mullen Lowe), London Junior Strategist, Dare, London Intelligence Planner, Tequila/London May 2015 to December 2022 January 2014 to May 2015 October 2009 to December 2013 January 2008 to October 2009 January 2007 to December 2007 November 2004 to April 2006

Sector Experience

Alcohol – Charity – Finance (Banking, Insurance, Investments & Pensions) – FMCG – Government & Public Sector – Media – Omnichannel Retail – Sustainability – Technology – Telecoms & Utilities – Travel & Transport

Recent Projects & Achievements at McCann

Brand and Communications Strategy: Leading integrated strategy, across advertising, social, PR and media, for all major clients; including development of Yeo Valley Organic's new brand platform "Yeo Got This!" and first advertising campaign in 10 years, complete repositioning of the UK's oldest brand, The Royal Mint, and six years of successful communications for Pink Lady apples, winning them a place on the UK Effies Shortlist in 2020.

Communications Planning & Customer Journeys: Development of audience segmentation, personas, touchpoint and customer journey mapping alongside an integrated team of media, social and digital specialists. End to end customer journey planning for Motability, Flybe, Brittany Ferries and The Royal Mint identified through the line communication opportunities and new projects across the integrated McCann team. It also led to the 2020 Cannes Lions winning initiative GoAbility for Motability.

Agency Growth & New Business: Strategic lead on all significant pitches; winning game changing clients Yeo Valley Organic, Motability, Thatchers Cider and Flybe, that quadrupled agency revenue across 7 years. Writing of public sector tenders, securing projects for The Royal Mint and West of England Combined Authority.

Insight Development & Managing Primary Research: Regularly running primary research pitches and procurement on behalf of clients and McCann. Identifying the need for primary insight, recommending providers and methodologies and briefing and managing third party providers. Led major research projects including U&A study and segmentation for The Royal Mint, global brand tracking for Pink Lady apples and campaign co-creation workshops with niche and diverse audiences for Forth healthcare and Motability.

Team Leadership and Strategic Coaching: Developed our successful Talks on Toast thought leadership programme of events and content. Trained all agency staff on McCann Truth 2 Meaning strategic tools and techniques. Ran regular creative thinking, briefing and feedback workshops for client and agency teams.

Other Career Highlights

- APG Strategic Management Masterclass Alumni 2022
- Google Digital Garage accredited 2022
- Meta Creative Strategy Distinction 2022
- 4 x Cannes Lions won for GoAbility in 2021
- MIPA Accredited since 2019
- UK Effie Shortlist 2018 for Small Luxury Hotels
- IPA Woman of Tomorrow, 2015
- WACL Future Leaders Prize 2009
- Gold IPA Effectiveness Award Winner 2008 for Halifax Students
- Campaign 30 Under 30 2008

Education

2023 Doctor of Philosophy, PHD Media & Communications, Bournemouth University
2015-2017 MA in Creative and Media Education, Bournemouth University
2000-2004 BA (hons) in Advertising and Marketing Communications, Bournemouth University

More About Me

I am a published academic, currently studying a PHD in Media & Communications, exploring the impact of diversity within creative teams on creative success in the advertising industry. I lecture in Advertising and Marketing at UWE, Bournemouth University and Southampton Solent. I also have a crazy 3-year-old son!